//import { SelectMultipleControlValueAccessor } from "@angular/forms";
import { Frage } from "./frage";

export const FRAGEN: Frage[] = [
    {
        fragenId: 1,
        fragetyp: 'multi',
        frage: 'What is true regarding UEFI firmware? (Choose two.)',
        antwort: ['It can read and interpret partition tables',
                  'It can use and read certain file systems',
                  'It stores its entire configuration on the /boot/ partition',
                  'It is stored in a special area within the GPT metadata',
                  'It is loaded from a fixed boot disk position'],
        antwortenId: [1,2,3,4,5],
        korrekteAntwort: [2,4],
      },
      {
        fragenId: 2,
        fragetyp: 'multi',
        frage: 'Which of the following examples for Bash file globbing matches a file named root-can-do-this.txt when used in the directory holding that file? (Choose three correct answers.)',
        antwort: ['root*can?do-this.{txt,odt}',
                  'r[oOoO]t-can-do*.txt',
                  '{root,user,admin}-can-??-this.txt',
                  'root*can*do??this.txt',
                  'root***{can,may}-do-this.[tT][xX][tT]'],
        antwortenId: [1,2,3,4,5],
        korrekteAntwort: [1,3,5],
      },
      {
        fragenId: 3,
        fragetyp: 'multi',
        frage: 'Which of the following are init systems used within Linux systems? (Choose THREE correct answers.)',
        antwort: ['startd',
                  'systemd',
                  'Upstart',
                  'SysInit',
                  'SysV init'],
        antwortenId: [1,2,3,4,5],
        korrekteAntwort: [2,3,5],
      },
      {
        fragenId: 4,
        fragetyp: 'multi',
        frage: 'Which of the following information is stored within the BIOS? (Choose TWO correct answers.)',
        antwort: ['Boot device order',
                  'Linux kernel version',
                  'Timezone',
                  'Hardware configuration',
                  'The system\'s hostname'],
        antwortenId: [1,2,3,4,5],
        korrekteAntwort: [1,4],
      },
      {
        fragenId: 5,
        fragetyp: 'multi',
        frage: 'Which of the following commands brings a system running SysV init into a state in which it is safe to perform maintenance tasks? (Choose TWO correct answers.)',
        antwort: ['shutdown -R 1 now',
                  'shutdown -single now',
                  'init 1',
                  'telinit 1',
                  'runlevel 1'],
        antwortenId: [1,2,3,4,5],
        korrekteAntwort: [3,4],
      },
      {
        fragenId: 6,
        fragetyp: 'multi',
        frage: 'Which of the following commands list all files and directories within the /tmp/ directory and its subdirectories which are owned by the user root? (Choose two.)',
        antwort: ['find /tmp -user root -print',
                  'find -path /tmp -uid root',
                  'find /tmp -uid root -print',
                  'find /tmp -user root',
                  'find -path /tmp -user root -print'],
        antwortenId: [1,2,3,4,5],
        korrekteAntwort: [1,4],
      },
      {
        fragenId: 7,
        fragetyp: 'multi',
        frage: 'Which of the following is true for hard linked files? (Choose three.)',
        antwort: ['The output of stat will report hard instead of regular file.',
                  'The hard linked files have the same permissions and owner.',
                  'The hard linked files share the same inode.',
                  'The hard linked files are indicated by a -> when listed with ls -l.',
                  'The hard linked files must be on the same filesystem.'],
        antwortenId: [1,2,3,4,5],
        korrekteAntwort: [2,3,5],
      },
      {
        fragenId: 8,
        fragetyp: 'single',
        frage: 'Which of the following commands makes /bin/foo executable by everyone but writable only by its owner?',
        antwort: ['chmod u=rwx,go=rx /bin/foo',
                  'chmod o+rwx,a+rx /bin/foo',
                  'chmod 577 /bin/foo',
                  'chmod 775 /bin/foo'],
        antwortenId: [1,2,3,4],
        korrekteAntwort: [1],
      },
      {
        fragenId: 9,
        fragetyp: 'single',
        frage: 'What is the first program the Linux kernel starts at boot time when using System V init?',
        antwort: ['/lib/init.so',
                  '/proc/sys/kernel/init',
                  '/etc/rc.d/rcinit',
                  '/sbin/init',
                  '/boot/init'],
        antwortenId: [1,2,3,4,5],
        korrekteAntwort: [4],
      },
      {
        fragenId: 10,
        fragetyp: 'single',
        frage: 'Which of the following commands will write a message to the terminals of all logged in users?',
        antwort: ['bcast',
                  'mesg',
                  'print',
                  'wall',
                  'yell'],
        antwortenId: [1,2,3,4,5],
        korrekteAntwort: [4],
      }, {
        fragenId: 11,
        fragetyp: 'single',
        frage: 'Which variable defines the directories in which a Bash shell searches for executable commands?',
        antwort: ['BASHEXEC',
                  'BASHRC',
                  'PATH',
                  'EXECPATH',
                  'PATHRC'],
        antwortenId: [1,2,3,4,5],
        korrekteAntwort: [3],
      }, {
        fragenId: 12,
        fragetyp: 'single',
        frage: 'Which of the following kernel parameters instructs the kernel to suppress most boot messages?',
        antwort: ['silent',
                  'verbose=0',
                  'nomesg',
                  'quiet'],
        antwortenId: [1,2,3,4],
        korrekteAntwort: [4],
      }, {
        fragenId: 13,
        fragetyp: 'single',
        frage: 'What does the ? symbol within regular expressions represent?',
        antwort: ['Match the preceding qualifier one or more times.',
                  'Match the preceding qualifier zero or more times.',
                  'Match the preceding qualifier zero or one times.',
                  'Match a literal ? character.'],
        antwortenId: [1,2,3,4],
        korrekteAntwort: [3],
      },
      {
        fragenId: 14,
        fragetyp: 'single',
        frage: 'Which of the following vi commands deletes two lines, the current and the following line?',
        antwort: ['d2',
                  '2d',
                  '2dd',
                  'dd2',
                  'de12'],
        antwortenId: [1,2,3,4,5],
        korrekteAntwort: [3],
      },
      {
        fragenId: 15,
        fragetyp: 'fill', 
        frage: 'Which command shows all shared libraries required by a binary executable or another shared library? (Specify ONLY the command without any path or parameters.)',
        antwort: [],
        antwortenId: [],
        korrekteAntwort: ['ldd'],
      },
      {
        fragenId: 16,
        fragetyp: 'fill', 
        frage: 'What is the name of the main configuration file for GNU GRUB? (Specify the file name only without any path.)',
        antwort: [],
        antwortenId: [],
        korrekteAntwort: ['grub.cfg'], // später noch andere Lösungen anbieten: other Answer: menu.lst, grub.conf, grub.cfg
      },
      {
        fragenId: 17,
        fragetyp: 'fill', 
        frage: 'Which Debian package management tool asks the configuration questions for a specific already installed package just as if the package were being installed for the first time? (Specify ONLY the command without any path or parameters.)',
        antwort: [],
        antwortenId: [],
        korrekteAntwort: ['dpkg-reconfigure'],
      },
      {
        fragenId: 18,
        fragetyp: 'fill', 
        frage: 'Typically, which top level system directory is used for files and data that change regularly while the system is running and are to be kept between reboots? (Specify only the top level directory)',
        antwort: [],
        antwortenId: [],
        korrekteAntwort: ['/var'],
      },
      {
        fragenId: 19,
        fragetyp: 'fill', 
        frage: 'The dpkg-____ command will ask configuration questions for a specified package, just as if the package were being installed for the first time. Answer: reconfigure',
        antwort: [],
        antwortenId: [],
        korrekteAntwort: ['reconfigure'],
      },
      {
        fragenId: 20,
        fragetyp: 'fill', 
        frage: 'Which command will display messages from the kernel that were output during the normal boot sequence?',
        antwort: [],
        antwortenId: [],
        korrekteAntwort: ['dmesg'], // other Answer: dmesg, /bin/dmesg
      },
      {
        fragenId: 21,
        fragetyp: 'fill', 
        frage: 'The USB device filesystem can be found under /proc/______/usb/. (Please fill in the blank with the single word only)',
        antwort: [],
        antwortenId: [],
        korrekteAntwort: ['bus'],
      },
]